Guide to the Jack L. Demmons Collection of Photographs of Bonner, Montana Circa 1890s-1960s
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- Clara Mae Moe, Andrew C. Moe, John C. (Jack) Moe as children, 12/11/19, 1919; Photo caption reads: Left to right, Clara Mae Moe, Andrew C. Moe, John C. (Jack) Moe. (Date typed on bottom corner of photo 12/11/19; young children; John with drum). Image from Photoboard #29 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 029_f_d)
- Kari Boarding House located near the Milltown Post Office, undated; Photo caption reads: The old Kari Boarding House, Located near the Milltown Post Office. (Three women on porch and one young girl). Image from Photoboard #29 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 029_h_d)
- Ben Soucie and John Karkanen at Clearwater Lake, August 1934, Photo caption reads: Ben Soucie (on the right) and John Karkanen coming from Clearwater Lake, Aug. 1934. (Holding four fish on stick between them). Image from Photoboard #29 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 029_i_d)
- Melvin Madsen, undated; Photo caption reads: Melvin Madsen. (Young man in yard; wood frame house behind him; mountain in background). Image from Photoboard #30 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 030_a_d)
- (Frank) Eino Heikkila and Melvin Madsen fishing in Placid Creek., undated; Photo caption reads: (Frank) Eino Heikkila and Melvin Madsen (bending down). Fishing in Placid Creek. (Boys). Image from Photoboard #30 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 030_b_d)
- Jack Erkkila in field, undated; Photo caption reads: Jack Erkkila. (In Bonner/Milltown field). Image from Photoboard #30 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 030_c_d)
- Jack Erkkila and Eino Weimer, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right: Jack Erkkila, Eino Weimer. (Outdoor). Image from Photoboard #30 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 030_d_d)
- Freida and Emma Jonasson in Sunne, Sweden, 1903, Photo caption reads: Freida and Emma Jonasson (Mrs. Nelson) (Mrs. Sampson) Age 20. Age 18. Taken in Sunne, Sweden, 1903. Image from Photoboard #30 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 030_e_d)
- Annie Olson, Trig Bergseth and John Sampson in 1930s? automobile, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right: Annie Olson, Trig Bergseth, John Sampson. (In 1930s? automobile; Trig a young boy on running board; near spot of Deer Creek Rifle Range in 2004). Image from Photoboard #30 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 030_g_d)
- Henry Petaja, Francis Hanson, Sime Petaja, George Petaja, Senia Petaja, undated; Photo caption reads: Henry Petaja, Francis Hanson, Sime Petaja, George Petaja, Senia Petaja. (Francis a young girl; with 1930s? vintage auto in woods). Image from Photoboard #30 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 030_h_d)
- River crew preparing to dislodge debris at the Bonner Dam, 1948, Photo caption reads: River crew preparing to dislodge debris at the Bonner Dam, 1948. Arne Karkanen, 2nd from Left. (Four men in bateau; front three standing; other man sits holding pole attached to plan from riverbank?; front man clutches cable mounted to pulley and thick cable strung across river). Image from Photoboard #31 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 031_a_d)
- Conrad Richlie taken at the Zaugg Farm, undated; Photo caption reads: Conrad Richlie. Taken at the Zaugg Farm. (Barn; work horse; West Riverside). Image from Photoboard #31 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 031_b_d)
- Arne Karkanen dislodging debris at the Bonner Dam, May, 1948, Photo caption reads: Arne Karkanen trying to dislodge debris at the Bonner Dam, May of 1948. (Stands alone in bateau; pole to downriver pile; opposite bank of Blackfoot behind). Image from Photoboard #31 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 031_c_d)
- Mrs. Anne Troop, Bonner School third grade teacher, undated; Photo caption reads: Mrs. Anne Troop, Bonner School third grade teacher. (Stands beneath two steps of "new" brick school looking out to playground). Image from Photoboard #31 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 031_d_d)
- PTA play, undated; Photo caption reads: PTA play, Bonner School. Front row - Lloyd Buckhouse, Melvin Madsen, George Buckhouse, Klaas de Wit, Art Akerson, Leo Gonsior, Cornelius de Wit. Back row: ___, Carl Johnson. (Adults; on school stage; musical instruments; costumes). Image from Photoboard #31 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 031_e_d)
- Conrad Richlie, U.S. Navy, World War II, undated; Photo caption reads: Conrad Richlie, U.S. Navy, World War II. (Stands in a yard in sailor uniform). Image from Photoboard #31 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 031_f_d)
- Dislodging debris at the Bonner Dam, 1948, Photo caption reads: Rivermen trying to dislodge debris at the Bonner Dam, 1948. Arne Karkanen at left. (Two men; same angle as third photo on this panel). Image from Photoboard #31 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 031_g_d)
- Arnold Zaugg and Conrad Richlie during World War II, undated; Photo caption reads: Arnold Zaugg and Conrad Richlie, During World War II. (Faded; dog with paws on running board of truck bed). Image from Photoboard #31 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 031_h_d)
- Debris at Bonner Dam, May 1948, Photo caption reads: Arne Karkanen trying to place plank at edge of boom to debris at Bonner Dam, May 1948. (Two men). Image from Photoboard #31 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 031_i_d)
- At Camp 9 in the Blackfoot, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right: 1. (blank) 2. (blank) 3. (blank) 4. Youngquist at Camp 9 in the Blackfoot. (Four men in aprons sit on hillside). Image from Photoboard #32 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 032_a_d)
- Camp 9 Cookhouse, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right: 1. __ 2. __ 3. __ 4. __ Youngquist. Camp 9 Cookhouse. (Four men; standing in cookhouse behind work table wielding rolling pins and other kitchen utensils; Youngquist, the shortest of the four, has a sword-size butcher knife in his right hand). Image from Photoboard #32 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 032_b_d)
- Dumping large rock from Blackfoot River into hole in Milltown Dam (1 of 5), undated; Photo caption reads: At Left, K.B. Frye (leftmost of 2 captions). Main caption reads: "Series of five pictures show the loading of a large rock in the area near the mouth of the Blackfoot River and dumping it in to a hole in the Milltown Dam in very early days." (Four men; winter). Image from Photoboard #32 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 032_c_d)
- Dumping large rock from Blackfoot River into hole in Milltown Dam (2 of 5), undated; No photo caption. (Five men in snow with large rock of preceding photo; two up on sled with right hands resting on rock, which has a chain around it and attached to a hoist above.). Image from Photoboard #32 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 032_d_d)
- Dumping large rock from Blackfoot River into hole in Milltown Dam (3 of 5), undated; Photo caption reads: Harry McCann. (Mustache, derby; stands with rock on platform at base of dam by powerhouse). Image from Photoboard #32 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 032_e_d)
- Dumping large rock from Blackfoot River into hole in Milltown Dam (4 of 5), undated; Photo caption reads: Harry McCann. K.B. Frye. (With rock on platform in snow on riverbank; not at dam). Image from Photoboard #32 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 032_f_d)
- Dumping large rock from Blackfoot River into hole in Milltown Dam (5 of 5), undated; No photo caption. (Shows rock sliding off platform into water below spillway). Image from Photoboard #32 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 032_g_d)
- Bonner street car in the East Missoula area., undated; Photo caption reads: The Bonner street car heading west. Picture was taken in what is now the East Missoula area. Marshall Canyon is to the left rear. (Woody Mountain in background too; tracks surrounded by heavy snow.). Image from Photoboard #32 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 032_h_d)
- East Side Milltown homes., undated; Photo caption reads: Picture taken of last row of homes on east side of Milltown. Left to right - Fred Johnson's, Langass (Nix Anderson before him), John Sampson's, and Heikkela home. (Sampson home seems to be two-story; deep snow in front of picket fence in front of houses). Image from Photoboard #33 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 033_a_d)
- Family in yard, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right: Emma Sampson, ___, Oscar Peterson, Allan Sampson in front. (Allan a boy; others adults; inside yard with picket fence; glimpse of log yard and Woody Mountain behind; Milltown?) Image from Photoboard #33 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 033_b_d)
- Nelson home after fire, undated; Photo caption reads: Remains of Freida and Peter John Nelson's home after fire. Image from Photoboard #33 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 033_c_d)
- People beside building, undated; No photo caption: (Four men in suits and one young girl in dress posing beside white building). Image from Photoboard #33 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 033_d_d)
- Esther and Allan Sampson, undated; Photo caption reads: Esther and Allan Sampson. Picture was taken at Lolo Hot Springs. (Sitting under large rock with initials AR painted on it). Image from Photoboard #33 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 033_e_d)
- Bonner School, undated; Photo caption reads: The original Bonner school, which was located just south of the railroad crossing at the north end of Bonner. Picture was taken near the turn of the century. (Schoolhouse; winter; snow on ground). Image from Photoboard #33 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 033_f_d)
- Gathering of Swedes, undated; Photo caption reads: A gathering of Swedes in Milltown. (Group of people; picket fence; homes and mountain in background). Image from Photoboard #33 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 033_g_d)
- School children, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right: Back row - Johnnie Fleming, Beatrice Haaglund, Clara Anderson, Bruce Winters, Marion Richlie, Bryon Lewis, Vivian Danielson, Joseph ___, Hazel Beadle. 3rd row - Gus ___, Arthur Lalem, Clara Moe, Taje Johnson, Martha ___, Alice Luce, Agnes Matson. 2nd row - Oran Paris, Paul ___, Ernest Ranta, Gordon Trenary, Gerda Nelson, Cornelius de Wit. Front row - Donald Mckay, Charlie Hamma, Nona Taylor, Carl Swanson, Lilian Akin, Evelyn Carlson. (Group of children standing on front steps of schoolhouse). Image from Photoboard #33 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 033_h_d)
- Group picture, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right: Back row - Mrs. John Anderson (grandson Conrad in front of her) Emma Sampson, ____, Mrs. Larsen, ____, Freida Nelson, ____, ____, Mrs. Anna Olson, Mrs. Tony Bergset (Norman in front of her.) Youngsters in front of Esther Sampson Hilda, Ruth, Tillie and Clarence Nelson. (Group standing in grass; picket fence building and mountain in background). Image from Photoboard #33 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 033_i_d)
- Hubald Doucette, Paul Thibodeau, Pat Thibodeau, and Jim Ryan, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right: Hubald Doucette, Paul Thibodeau, Pat Thibodeau, Jim Ryan. (Bonner; three men one boy standing on front porch of home). Image from Photoboard #34 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 034_a_d)
- Hauling blanks, undated; No photo caption. (Two horse team pulling wagon; loaded with blanks in snow; Two men on boards). Image from Photoboard #34 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 034_b_d)
- Workers at the mill, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right: ???, Carl (Cullie) Johnson, Joe Jacobson, Tot Sowre. (Four workers sitting at mill). Image from Photoboard #34 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 034_c_d)
- Portrait of a lady, undated; No photo caption: (Close-up of woman wearing furs). Image from Photoboard #34 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 034_d_d)
- Road Poll Tax receipt, 1932; No photo caption: (Photocopy: Road Poll Tax Receipt for 1932. City of Missoula. Dated July 14, 1932. Received of Olli? Hallgren, $3.00. One days work. "In full for Road Poll Tax in city of Missoula for 1932. H.K. Powell, City Clerk. George K. Dick, City Treasure. Signed by L.O. Hagan???). Image from Photoboard #34 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 034_e_d)
- Our Savior's Lutheran church, undated; No photo caption: (Our Savior's Lutheran Church). Image from Photoboard #34 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 034_f_d)
- Gardens, undated; Photo caption reads: Gardens near Anaconda Mill in Bonner. (between WWI and WWII). Image from Photoboard #34 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 034_g_d)
- Bonner churches, undated; No photo caption: (Two Bonner churches; looking north; Lutheran church in foreground with Model A's and people in front in snow). Image from Photoboard #34 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 034_h_d)
- Harpers Lake picnic., undated; Photo caption reads: Early days photo taken by Sowres. ("Harper's Lake" handwritten at bottom of photo; tent; two Model A's and family picnic in foreground). Image from Photoboard #34 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 034_i_d)
- George Mahrt Sr., George Mahrt Jr., Fred Kniffen, 1946; Photo caption reads: 1946. George Mahrt Sr., George Mahrt Jr., Fred Kniffen. (George Jr. in Army dress uniform). Image from Photoboard #35 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 035_a_d)
- Sheep graze at base of Bonner mountain, 1930; Photo caption reads: Bonner 5/11/30. (Sheep graze at base of Bonner mountain). Image from Photoboard #35 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 035_b_d)
- Mrs. Fred Kniffen, Mrs. Frank Farmer, 1942, Photo caption reads: Mrs. Fred Kniffen, Mrs. Frank Farmer. Taken 1942 during WWII. (In nurse uniforms; arms around each other's waist; in yard). Image from Photoboard #35 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 035_c_d)
- George Buckhouse in front of George's Café, undated; Photo caption reads: George Buckhouse. (Stands in front of George's Café; apron; white baker's hat). Image from Photoboard #35 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 035_d_d)
- Bonner - Late 1800's, circa 1800s; Photo caption reads: 1st schoolhouse - with bell tower, far rear. Bonner - Late 1800's. (Frontier lumber camp; looking up canyon; very smoky). Image from Photoboard #35 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 035_e_d)
- Ethel A. Farmer, age 80, undated; Photo caption reads: Ethel A. Farmer, age 80. (Head and shoulders photo). Image from Photoboard #35 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 035_f_d)
- Bonner looking toward Missoula, aerial view, undated; Photo caption reads: Mill looking toward Missoula. (Aerial view from mouth of canyon; Heaven Rock; Milwaukee trestle; both dams; Mount Jumbo). Image from Photoboard #35 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 035_g_d)
- Bonner Roundhouse, undated; Photo caption reads: Bonner Roundhouse. 1st schoolhouse, far right. (School is old Masonic Lodge; no bell tower; present-day post office building and former George's Café has Model A parked in front with large billboard "Bill's"; "Candies, Tobaccos, Cold Drinks"). Image from Photoboard #35 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 035_h_d)
- Mr. and Mrs. Emery Madsen, Mr. and Mrs. Melvin Madsen sit at dinner table, undated; Photo caption reads: Madsens lived In house that is presently personnel office. Mr. And Mrs. Emery Madsen, Mr. And Mrs. Melvin Madsen. (Sitting at dinner table). Image from Photoboard #35 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 035_i_d)
- Old Bonner School with slab wood stacked on right side, undated; Photo caption reads: Old Bonner School. (Piles of lumber on right side). Image from Photoboard #36 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 036_a_d)
- Looking toward Missoula from mountain, undated; Photo caption reads: Looking towards Missoula. (Shot from "B" on Bonner Mountain?; overlooks old school; both churches; lumber yard; all of Milltown; Western Lumber mill across river with full yard (pre 1932?); Milltown Dam; Mount Jumbo saddle in far background). Image from Photoboard #36 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 036_b_d)
- Old Bonner School in snow, undated; Photo caption reads: Old Bonner School. (In snow; cars parked outside; children play on snowbank). Image from Photoboard #36 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 036_c_d)
- Tearing down old school, undated; Photo caption reads: Tearing down old school. (Corner of present-day "bus garage" visible to left; men stand on stairs and on main floor; with front wall and roof missing; part of swing set visible in foreground). Image from Photoboard #36 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 036_d_d)
- Bonner School, Catholic and Lutheran Churches, undated; Photo caption reads: Bonner School, Catholic and Lutheran Churches. (Old school; no B on Bonner Mountain). Image from Photoboard #36 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 036_e_d)
- Dedication: first tree planted at the Bonner School, undated; Photo caption reads: Dedication: 1st tree planted at the Bonner School. (Old school; many students and teachers involved; principal Akin? stands with arms crossed at far right). Image from Photoboard #36 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 036_f_d)
- Conrad Richlie as a boy, undated; Photo caption reads: Conrad Richlie. (Close-up photo; original photo torn across Conrad's right cheek). Image from Photoboard #36 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 036_g_d)
- Miss Violette's school class, undated; Photo caption reads: First row L to R: Marcus Nearman .... Ethel Fish, Rita Thibodeau, Edith Salmonson. Second row L to R: Clifford Swanson, Paul Blanchard, Hilda Halvari, Tom Nelson, ..., Lars Nelson Ted Egan. To Miss Violette's left: Esther Montelius ... Julia Anderson, Birdie Alger. (Primary grade or grades; old school; many more students than identified in photo). Image from Photoboard #36 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 036_h_d)
- School class about 1913, 5th and 6th grades, circa 1913; Photo caption reads: Front row, left to right: Bill Weimer, George Cyr, ...., Ed Labbe, John Markel, Guy Olson. Back row: 3rd from left - Ted Benjamin. (Penciled in alongside captions: "About 1913, 5th and 6th grade. 2nd row: Hazel Egan, Benjamin daughter, Peterson girl. (under front row ID's) George Hodgson. Back row: 1st Hazel Fowler, 2nd Bill Lien, 4th Rasler?? Lien. 3rd row: Dorothy Gaseon?? another postmaster). Image from Photoboard #36 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 036_i_d)
- Don Ruby, undated; Photo caption reads:Don Ruby. (Man in white t-shirt, fedora; picket fence, Bonner homes). Image from Photoboard #37 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 037_a_d)
- Wilbur Lehman as a boy near old Mullan Road, undated; Photo caption reads: Wilbur Lehman. Old Mullan Road was to his left. (Boy in old-fashioned boy's outfit, standing on rock in Milltown where I-90 is today; Milltown Dam, overlook and reservoir in background downstream). Image from Photoboard #37 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 037_b_d)
- Joe Boileau fishing, undated; Photo caption reads: Joe Boileau. (Man in hat stands with fish in right hand and net in left). Image from Photoboard #37 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 037_c_d)
- Emil Elo, undated; Photo caption reads: Emil Elo. (Studio photo; man in suit and tie sits in chair, leg crossed with unidentified book open). Image from Photoboard #37 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 037_d_d)
- McCloskey children by a stream, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right: Florence McCloskey, Dorothea Applequist, Marie McCloskey, Bernice McCloskey, John McCloskey. Jim McCloskey in back. (Children stand by unidentified stream; girls in dresses; Florence with hat; Florence and Dorothea holding sticks in stream). Image from Photoboard #37 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 037_e_d)
- Bernard Nantt and bear, undated; Photo caption reads: Bernard Nantt and bear. Taken in West Riverside. (Bernard holds dead bear by scruff of neck; house, woodpile in background). Image from Photoboard #37 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 037_f_d)
- Group in front of frame house, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right: Identity of individuals undated, except for Severenna McDaniels at the far right. (Two men, four women, older girl, and two small boys stand in front of frame house). Image from Photoboard #37 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 037_g_d)
- Fred R. Thibodeau, bartender, 1908; Photo caption reads: Fred R. Thibodeau, at a Milltown bar, 1908. (Bartender behind bar, arms folded; possibly what is now Harold’s Club). Image from Photoboard #37 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 037_h_d)
- Chris, Jim and John Magnusson working in ACM gardens, undated; Photo caption reads: From left to right, Chris, Jim and John Magnusson at work in the ACM Gardens. (Man and two boys, hoeing and shoveling in rough terrain; teepee burner, white building that is possibly the company store, mountain in background). Image from Photoboard #37 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 037_i_d)
- Walking across suspension bridge over the spillway of the Milltown Dam, undated; Photo caption reads: Simi Petaja (?). Walking across the top of the spillway at the Milltown Dam. (Western Lumber mill in back). Image from Photoboard #38 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 038_a_d)
- Boy and father with boxing gloves, undated; No photo caption. (Boy and father with boxing gloves; Riverside Park?; Wood of W. Riverside?). Image from Photoboard #38 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 038_b_d)
- Western Lumber Company and the old Black Highway Bridge, undated; Photo caption reads: Looking to the southwest towards the old western mill and the old Black Highway Bridge. (Logs on river). Image from Photoboard #38 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 038_c_d)
- Skiers on Sheep Mountain, March 1945, Photo caption reads: 1. Donald Rooney. 2. Bill Demmons. 3. Jack Demmons. On top of Sheep Mountain with Grant Higgins, March, 1945. (On skis; snow on ground). Image from Photoboard #38 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 038_d_d)
- Florence Fowler Rooney and Hazel Fowler on horses, undated; Photo caption reads: Florence Fowler Rooney, Hazel Fowler. (On horses). Image from Photoboard #38 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 038_e_d)
- Ernest Hunt, World War II, undated; Photo caption reads: Ernest Hunt, World War II. (Head and shoulders photo). Image from Photoboard #38 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 038_f_d)
- Charlotte Brauer, Mabelle Dohrovalony and other children at picnic, undated; Photo caption reads: Left to right - 1. Charlotte Brauer. 2. Mabell Dohrovalony. 3. ____. (Other children in background; school picnic; Marco Flats?). Image from Photoboard #38 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 038_g_d)
- Alice Langraff as a girl, undated; Photo caption reads: Alice Langraff. (Head photo; handwritten below name is the word "Langas"). Image from Photoboard #38 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 038_h_d)
- Class of Ada Lalonde Richlie at Huson, undated; Photo caption reads: Class of Ada Lalonde Richlie at Huson. (Caption is handwritten on yellow notepad paper). Image from Photoboard #40 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 040_a_d)
- Myrtle and Einar Lehti 45th wedding anniversary portrait, undated; Photo caption reads: Myrtle and Einar Lehti. Taken at 45th wedding anniversary. Image from Photoboard #40 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number 040_b_d)